Jonathan Oliveira

Software Engineer

Passionate Software Engineer with 9 years of experience. Working professionally as full-stack developer for 6 years, focused on Java, Spring, AngularJS, HTML. Fast learner, software craftsmanship believer, problem-solver with can-do attitude, willing to deliver high quality software.



Maringa, Brazil

Maringa, Brazil

contato@jonathanoliveira.com

+55 44 9946-2606

Vancouver, BC

jonathan oliveira



Work Experience

12/2009 - 06/2013

Software Engineer

investor\$Tec @ investor\$Inc (personal project)

Real State Management Software for an international real estate advisory company.

Tasks/Achievements

- Displayed a really full stack role, from requirements gathering and project management to coding, deployment and server administration.
- Achieved fully continuous integration and continuous deploy environment with Bitbucket, Codeship and Heroku with virtually 100% app uptime.
- Managed many project challenges, such as cloud databases and large files and images uploads to the cloud (over 18k images).
- Automated several marketing processes such as brochure generation and homes images manipulations.
- Developed a REST API to integrate data to different websites.

Contact: Leandro Teles - teles@investorsinc.com.br

08/2014 - Present

Software Engineer

Objective Solutions

http://www.objective.com.br/

Tasks/Achievements

- Participated in the development and maintenance of a large CRM & Billing system with Java and internal frameworks.
- Worked with several satellite systems with different technologies such as Javascript, JSF, and HTML/CSS.
- Took the initiative to change technologies of a JSF project to AngularJS, meeting client's tight deadlines and budget.
- Teached AngularJS and Spring to the other team members.
- Member of a development team with strong agile practices such as SCRUM, pair programming, code review, CI, XP and Kanban.

Contact: Joel Matsu - +55 44 9106-5675

06/2013 - 08/2014

Maringa, Brazil

Senior Java Developer

DB1 Global Software

http://www.db1.com.br

Tasks/Achievements

- Participated in outsourcing projects, with Java, defining architecture, programming, delegating tasks and keeping follow-ups with other programmers.
- Automated several HR internal processes by making surveys, analysing processes and developing a software to help HR do things faster and easier.
- Worked as a SCRUM Master of the development team and performed tasks of lesser complexity inherent in project management.
- Participated in an innovation project conducted internally with "My Loyalty Card".

Contact: Edoil Barros - +55 44 9125-1206

Education

01/2006 - 12/2014

Bachelor of Computer Science

State University of Maringa

Courses

- Compilers
- Artificial intelligenceProgramming languages
- Software engineering
 - Algorithms
 - Algorithms analysis

Skills & Competences

			1	
Java/Sp	ring			
Angular	ıs			
Aligotal	, , , , , , , , , , , , , , , , , , ,			
lavacci	ob/LITAAL/			
Javazcii	pt/HTML/0	.33		
SQL				
.Net				
Ionic				
UX/UI de	esign			
Intellij II	DEA			
Codeshi	p/Heroku			

Personal Projects

My Loyalty Card

 Simple desktop app for managing loyalty cards and customers points for restaurants and retailers in general.

NetAnimations

 Learning Object Repository of Computer Networking discipline of Computer Science course at State University of Maringá. Mobile app built with Ionic.

My Games App

 Simple app to register, keep track and share my platforms and games. Building with Ionic Framework.

Languages

Portuguese

Native or Bilingual

Enalish

Upper-intermediate

Spanish

Beginne

Interests

Java | Spring | Javascript | Web development |
Software craftsmanship | Cloud computing | IoT |

Clean code | Continuous delivery |

Continuous integration